MIKE DENTON

I'm a user experience designer with over 7 years experience designing online apps and websites for companies such as Xero and Mitsubishi Electric.

I've led the design of financial software and marketing websites. I love working closely with customers and software teams to understand peoples' needs, explore solutions, and deliver better experiences.

PHONE

07810 535294

EMAIL

contact@mikedenton.design

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/mike-denton

PORTFOLIO

mikedenton.design

EXPERIENCE

Xero • Senior Product Designer 4 Years, 2013-17

Xero create online accounting software that over 1 million businesses rely on. At Xero I led the redesign of Xero's financial reporting tools. I worked closely with agile software teams to help them learn more about their customers, explore design solutions, and build a quality product.

- · Led the redesign of Xero's financial reporting tools.
- · Conducted foundation research into how customers track their finances.
- Designed an online editor for accountants producing financial documents.
- Designed tools to automatically file sales tax and other forms online.

Xero • Marketing Designer 1 Year, 2012–13

As a marketing designer I helped attract new customers to Xero. I made improvements to the marketing website and created promotional material.

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Designed custom landing pages to increase conversion rates.
- · Designed a careers section to attract more talent.
- · Created online ads and print campaigns.

Mitsubishi Electric • Graphic Designer 1 Year, 2011–12

At Mitsubishi Electric I led the redesign of their website and created marketing material to promote the brand and it's products.

- · Led the redesign of mitsubishi-electric.co.nz
- · Produced a industry magazine and various product catalogues.
- · Created ads for magazines, billboards and point of sale.

Self-Employed • Web Designer 1 Year, 2010-11

I designed and built websites for a range of clients including a lawn mowing company, an online legal service, and an outdoor advertising company.

- · Meet with clients and managed the design process.
- · Designed and built websites using Wordpress, HTML and CSS.

SKILLS

User Research

- · Usability Testing
- Customer Interviews
- · Data & Analytics

Interaction Design

- User Objectives
- Interface Design
- · Content & Structure

Prototyping

- Wireframing
- · Visual Mockups
- · HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Master of Design

User Centered Design Massey University, 2010

Bachelor of Design

Visual Communication Massey University, 2008